<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>An R reproducibility toolkit for the practical researcher</title>
    <link>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/</link>
    <description>Recent content on An R reproducibility toolkit for the practical researcher</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Day 0</title>
      <link>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/day0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/day0/</guid>
      <description>Hi! In this workshop we will be introducing in many tools to help make your work as reproducible as possible. That means that you’ll need to have several programs installed and set up before we begin. Please, follow these instructions before the workshop.
R At the very least you need to have R installed on your computer. If possible, try to have it upgraded to the latest version. We developed the materials using R version 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mini Reprohack</title>
      <link>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/reprohack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/reprohack/</guid>
      <description>One of the best ways of learning what makes a reproducible project is to try to reproduce real life projects instead of toy examples. You&amp;rsquo;ll quickly learn what works and what doesn&amp;rsquo;t and pick up tools and workflows from others.
Therefore we propose this optional homework in which you will do just that. You can do it at any moment during the workshop. Some paper require using particular packages or technologies that you might not be familiar at the start of the workshop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extras</title>
      <link>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/extras/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/extras/</guid>
      <description>Parameterised reports     Sometimes you need to re-do a report changing one variable that repeats over all the code, the best way to do this is through a parameterised report.
In the following example there is a plot of the price distribution for ideal diamonds. If you want to change it to visualise the data for &amp;ldquo;fair&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;very good&amp;rdquo; cut diamonds, you will have to change the filter(cut == &amp;quot;Ideal&amp;quot;) and hopefully you wont forget the plot title.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
