<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>An R reproducibility toolkit for the practical researcher</title>
    <link>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/</link>
    <description>Recent content on An R reproducibility toolkit for the practical researcher</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01: Reproducible computational environment with renv</title>
      <link>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/day3/01-renv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/day3/01-renv/</guid>
      <description>No code is its own isolated bubble. Almost every analysis will depend on a number of external packages, such as ggplot2 for plotting, data.table for data wrangling, knitr for rendering a report, and so on.
But actively-maintained packages will change their code-base to fix bugs, add features, remove features or change behaviour. These changes have the potential of breaking your analysis or creating subtle (or not so subtle) differences in the result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>01: What is repdoducibilty anyway?</title>
      <link>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/day1/01-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/day1/01-introduction/</guid>
      <description>This workshop will introduce some useful tools to help you write code that can be run anywhere with consistent results. We will focus on the practical aspects of reproducibility, but it’s still worth it to get some sense of what is reproducibility and what’s its aim.
What reproducibility is and what it is not We will use “reproducibility” to talk about results that can be obtained by someone else given the same data and code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02: Reproducible computational environment with Docker</title>
      <link>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/day3/02-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/day3/02-docker/</guid>
      <description>While renv is nice, it doesn’t solve the whole problem, because system dependencies and even the R version itself can change. Another issue is that downloading and installing all the R packages can take a while. Like an hour or more. This is not a deal-breaker, but I’d like to do better. People trying to reproduce work are few and far between, so it’s important to make their lives as easy as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 0</title>
      <link>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/day0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/day0/</guid>
      <description>Hi! In this workshop we will be introducing in many tools to help make your work as reproducible as possible. That means that you’ll need to have several programs installed and set up before we begin. Please, follow these instructions before the workshop.
R At the very least you need to have R installed on your computer. If possible, try to have it upgraded to the latest version. We developed the materials using R version 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02: A tidy project is a happy project</title>
      <link>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/day1/02-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/day1/02-projects/</guid>
      <description>Imagine that you read some interesting paper or analysis. To your delight, all the code and data is available in a public repository. You then are itching to sink your teeth on it; to see how they implemented the methods, or to run it with your own similar data.
You download the all the files and you find something like this.
# TODO: mover esto para que la ruta de la carpeta no sea tan larga?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02: Research compendia with rrtools</title>
      <link>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/day2/02-rrtools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/day2/02-rrtools/</guid>
      <description>Of course, you can always create a file structure that suit you and your work by hand. But here we are going to try rrtools to create a “research compendium” and combine it with the things we learned on the git and GitHub section.
The first thing you need to know is that an rrtools compendium will be at the same time an R package. If you don’t have experience with R packages, don’t worry!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elio Campitelli</title>
      <link>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/people/eliocampitelli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/people/eliocampitelli/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a Ph.D. student at the University of Buenos Aires in atmospheric sciences and an R package developer. I apply open science principles with a strong emphasis on reproducibility by publicly making all the code and data available. I&amp;rsquo;m a founding member of the R User Group in Buenos Aires and an outstanding contributor to the LatinR conference (as recognized by LatinR founding chairs). I maintain several open-source R packages (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paola Corrales</title>
      <link>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/people/paocorrales/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/people/paocorrales/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a Ph.D. student at the University of Buenos Aires. I study atmospheric sciences applying data assimilation techniques to improve short-term forecasts of severe events in Argentina. Also, I&amp;rsquo;m a Trainer and instructor for The Carpentries and an RStudio certified instructor. I co-funded MetaDocencia, a Spanish-speaking community to help teachers and educator to apply science-based techniques to their clase.s
I develops openly licensed materials to teach and learn R from scratch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03: Reporting with RMarkdown</title>
      <link>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/day1/03-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/day1/03-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>RMarkdown files An RMarkdown file is a plain text file, with some rules and special syntax that allow us to write code and text together. When it is “knitted,” the code will be evaluated and executed and the text formatted so that it creates a reproducible report or document that is nice to read and contains all your work.
This is really critical to reproducibility. It also saves us time and can help with automation tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03: Sharing data</title>
      <link>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/day2/03-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/day2/03-data/</guid>
      <description>The two ingredients for a reproducible project are code and data. We talked a lot about how to organise and share code, but what about data? Sharing data is far from trivial and there are a lot of things to consider.
Permissions Before the technical issues of sharing data there are the bureaucratic issues. Depending on your context, you might not be allowed to share your data. Data can be expensive to create so your company or institution might want to keep it private so they can squeeze all the profit it can from it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04: here are the portable paths</title>
      <link>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/day1/04-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/day1/04-here/</guid>
      <description>If you use RStudio Projects consistently, you can be sure that your working directory is always the root of the project unless you actively change it. Almost. There are two situations in which this assumption can be broken and that can lead to errors or, even worse, surprising results.
Root directory during knit One issue is that when RMarkdown files are knitted, the working directory in which the code is executed is the location of the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extras</title>
      <link>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/extras/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/extras/</guid>
      <description>Parameterised reports Sometimes you need to re-do a report changing one variable that repeats over all the code, the best way to do this is through a parameterised report.
In the following example there is a plot of the price distribution for ideal diamonds. If you want to change it to visualise the data for “fair” or “very good” cut diamonds, you will have to change the filter(cut == &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attribution</title>
      <link>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/attribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/attribution/</guid>
      <description>Sheep drawing by Gordon Johnson from Pixabay
Pixel Cells by Manfred Steger from Pixabay
Icon: Sheep by Adriansyah from NounProject.com
Day 1 sheep: Image by OpenClipart-Vectors from Pixabay</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
