<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Day 1 on An R reproducibility toolkit for the practical researcher</title>
    <link>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/day1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Day 1 on An R reproducibility toolkit for the practical researcher</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/day1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 - What is repdoducibilty anyway?</title>
      <link>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/day1/01-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/day1/01-introduction/</guid>
      <description>  Why is it important.
Why would you want to make your code reproducible.
Reproducibilty vs. replicability.
Limits of reproducibility.
Reproducibilty-transparency trade-off
Reproducibility doesn’t mean correct code, nor replicability means correct science!
What is real
Exercises  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03: Reporting with RMarkdown</title>
      <link>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/day1/03-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/day1/03-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>RMarkdown files An RMarkdown file is a plain text file, with some rules and special syntax that allow us to write code and text together. When it is “knited,” the code will be evaluated and executed and the text formatted so that it creates a reproducible report or document that is nice to read and contains all your work.
This is really critical to reproducibility. It also saves us time and can help with automation tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 - A tidy project is a happy project</title>
      <link>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/day1/02-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eliocamp.github.io/reproducibility-with-r/materials/day1/02-projects/</guid>
      <description>Imagine that you read some interesting paper or analysis. To your delight, all the code and data is available in a public repository. You then are itching to sink your teeth on it; to see how they implemented the methods, or to run it with your own similar data.
You download the all the files and you find something like this.
# TODO: mover esto para que la ruta de la carpeta no sea tan larga?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
